Guide to the W.H. Cowley Papers SC0196
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal papers and writings, Series 1
  - Correspondence, writings and speeches, 1922-1978; Series 1B
    - Correspondence with Johnshoy, Howard, G. about his proposed joint book on academic government., 1951 Jun-1953 Sep (Box 24, Folder 53-18)
    - Correspondence with Reid, J.M. and Spalding, Willard about the latter's use and loss of WHC's lecture notes., 1951 Jul-1953 Nov (Box 24, Folder 53-19)
    - Correspondence with Morrill, J.L. about a review for him of British universities and educators that he should visit on his trip to England., 1953 Jan-Apr (Box 24, Folder 53-20)
    - Correspondence with Lord Simon of Wythenshawe about academic government., 1952 Jun-1953 Oct (Box 24, Folder 53-21)
    - Student criticisms of WHC's course, Educ. 308., 1953 Aug-Dec (Box 24, Folder 53-22)
    - Correspondence relating to WHC talk give to the American Association for University Professors, San Jose State College chapter. Copy of speech not included., 1953 Nov-Dec (Box 24, Folder 53-23)
    - Correspondence with the University of Minnesota, chiefly Williamson, E.G. and the University Press people about publishing a book of WHC's., 1953 Jan-1958 Feb (Box 24, Folder 53-24)
    - Correspondence with Prentice-Hall, Inc. about publishing a book., 1953 Apr-Nov (Box 24, Folder 53-25)
    - "Ways of Defining Education," 10th topic, WHC course, Introduction to American Higher Education, 11 pages. (Box 24, Folder 53-26)
    - "Who Can Educate," 11th topic, WHC course, Intro to American Higher Education, 10 pages. (Box 24, Folder 53-27)
    - Correspondence with Reed, Glenn about proposed book co-authored with WHC., 1953 Jul-1962 Sep (Box 24, Folder 53-28)
    - Correspondence with Norman J. DeWitt., 1953-1967 (Box 24, Folder 53-29)
    - "Generalized vs. Specialized Education," WHC consulting job for Eurich, A.C., and the Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education, 15 pages., 1954 Feb 11 (Box 24, Folder 54-1)
    - "Religion and Academic Freedom," text of talk given for Miller, Alex, Stanford., 1954 Jan 28 (Box 24, Folder 54-2)
    - WHC book review for the Journal of Higher Education of Richard J. Storr’s The Beginnings of Graduate Education in America. Pages, 104-105., 1954 Feb (Box 24, Folder 54-3)
    - "Which Liberal Arts Colleges Should be Assisted Financially?" WHC memo for the Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education. Also includes related correspondence and notes., 1954 Feb-Mar (Box 24, Folder 54-4)
    - "The Breadth Versus Depth Controversy in American Higher Education," WHC memo for the Fund for the Advancement of Education. 11 pages. See also 56-8., 1954 Mar (Box 24, Folder 54-5)
    - "Should Course Offerings Be Pruned?" Improving College and University Teaching, pages. 20-24. Originally a memo to Starcher, Dean G.W. of Ohio State University written at the suggestion of Eurich, A.C.. This folder also contains correspondence with Eurich and Starcher., 1954 Feb-May (Box 24, Folder 54-6)
    - "Survey Report of the United States Armed Forces Institute," WHC consulting work, 12 pages., 1954 Mar 13 (Box 24, Folder 54-7)
    - "The Higher Education Unit in the Stanford University School of Education," WHC memo written for Quillen, Dean I.J. 25 pages. Also contains correspondence with Quillen., 1954 Apr (Box 24, Folder 54-8)
    - "The Miracle," WHC paper written for Tina, 6 pages., 1954 Dec (Box 24, Folder 54-9)
    - "Are Professors Human?" outline of WHC address at the San Jose State Class dinner. Also includes related correspondence., 1954 Jun (Box 24, Folder 54-10)
    - "A Proposed Volume Entitled Documents of American Higher Education," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Higher Education, 14 pages., 1954 Aug 25 (Box 24, Folder 54-11)
    - "The Academic Lazzaroni," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Education. 9 pages. See also 54-17., 1954 Sep 1 (Box 24, Folder 54-12)
    - "Four Memoranda on the Status of Educationists," WHC memo for the faculty of the Stanford University School of Education. 29 pages. See also 54-12 and 54-17., 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 54-12A)
    - "Some Ideas for Educational Designers," WHC memo for the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 26 pages., 1954 Sep (Box 24, Folder 54-13)
    - "Improving Educational News," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 18 pages., 1954 Sep (Box 24, Folder 54-14)
    - Papers related to WHC's inauguration as Jacks, David, Professor of Higher Education, Stanford. Folder includes invitation, news clippings, and related correspondence., 1954 Jan-1955 Feb (Box 24, Folder 54-16A)
    - "The Higher Learning Versus the Higher Education," WHC's inauguration speech as Jacks, David, Professor. pages. 29-44. Also contains first draft., 1954 Apr (Box 24, Folder 54-16B)
    - "The Higher Learning Versus the Higher Education," Jacks, David, ceremony speech reprinted in The Kansai University Bulletin, 5 pages., 1954 May (Box 25, Folder 54-16C)
    - "The Higher Learning Versus the Higher Education," Jacks, David, ceremony speech reprinted in the Punjab Education Journal pages. Pages 260-279., 1954 Aug (Box 25, Folder 54-16D)
    - "The Higher Learning Versus the Higher Education,” Jacks, David, ceremony speech reprinted in the Journal of Higher Education, pages 401-454., 1954 Nov (Box 25, Folder 54-16E)
    - "Criticisms of Educationists," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Education. 11 pages. Includes related correspondence. See also 54/12 and 54-17., 1954 Dec-1955 Mar (Box 25, Folder 54-17)
    - "Accreditation Report, Schedule A: School of Education of Stanford," prepared by Quillen, I.J., and WHC, 18 pages., 1954 Nov (Box 25, Folder 54-18)
    - "The School of Education at Stanford University," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 18 pages., 1954 Nov (Box 25, Folder 54-18A)
    - "The Government or Policy Control of American Higher Education," topic 26 of WHC course, An Intro to American Higher Education, pages 264-277., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-19)
    - "The Administration or Operational Control of American Higher Education," topic 27 in WHC course, An Intro to American Higher Education, pages 281-289., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-20)
    - "The American College Student," topic 4, WHC's Student Personnel Course, 19 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-21)
    - "The American College Professor," topic 5, WHC student personnel course, 10 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-22)
    - "The American College Administrator," topic 6, WHC student personnel course, 7 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-23)
    - "Student Personnel Workers," topic 7, WHC student personnel course, 4 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-24)
    - "Admissions," topic 8, WHC student personnel course, 7 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-25)
    - "Financial Aids," topic 11 of student personnel course, 11 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-26)
    - "Health Services," topic 12, WHC student personnel course, 7 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-27)
    - "The Extracurricular," topic 13, WHC student personnel course, 9 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-28)
    - "Extracurricular Services Managed by the Institution," topic 14, WHC student personnel course, 7 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-29)
    - "Services Usually Managed by Students," topic 15, WHC student personnel course, 5 pages., Spring 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-30)
    - Papers related to WHC's participation in a seminar at the Industrial Management Institute of the University of Wisconsin, Madison., 1954 Mar-Nov (Box 25, Folder 54-31)
    - Assistance to the Dean of the Women's College of the University of North Carolina, correspondence re., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-32)
    - Correspondence with Frank W. Wachsmith about counseling his son before his death in an automobile accident., 1954 Oct-Dec (Box 25, Folder 54-33)
    - Correspondence with the U.S. Office of Education about standard terminology in higher education., 1953-1957 (Box 25, Folder 54-34)
    - WHC analysis for Harmon, W.W., Professor of Engineering at Stanford, of his plans for a course on the teaching of engineering, 2 pages., 1953 Dec 6 (Box 25, Folder 54-35)
    - Correspondence with Clark, Evans., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-36)
    - WHC letter to Eurich, Alvin, C., reporting status of work done for the Fund for the Advancement of Education. 2 pages. Includes discussion of taped interview with Wood, James M. See also 55-16., 1954 Nov 27 (Box 25, Folder 54-37)
    - "The Terminology of the Educational Function," topic 12, WHC course, An Intro to American Higher Education, 22 pages., 1954 Fall (Box 25, Folder 54-38)
    - "The Financing of American Higher Education," topic 28, WHC course, Intro to Am. Higher Education, pages 319-321., 1954 Fall (Box 25, Folder 54-39)
    - Three papers by Professor Wentworth, Gerald, on the administration of higher education at the request of WHC., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 54-40)
    - Topic A: "The Background of Financing colleges and Universities," 11 pages, plus bibliography. (Box 25, Folder 54-40A)
    - Topic B: "Financing Colleges and Universities-Raising the Money," 18 pages. (Box 25, Folder 54-40B)
    - Topic C: "Financing Colleges and Universities-Managing the Funds," 10 pages. (Box 25, Folder 54-40C)
    - Correspondence about WHC’s career at Stanford., 1955 Jan-Oct (Box 25, Folder 55-1)
    - Papers relating to the Western College Association study of the University of California-Berkeley, 10 pages., 1955 Jan (Box 25, Folder 55-2)
    - Papers concerning a School of Education faculty meeting where WHC's "Four Memoranda on the status of Educationists," was discussed. See also 55-13., 1954 Feb 18 (Box 25, Folder 55-3)
    - "The Heritage and Purposes of Higher Education," WHC address to the Western College Association, Proceedings of the Western College Association, pages. 53-61. Includes related correspondence., 1955 Jan-Apr (Box 25, Folder 55-4A)
    - 55-4A reprinted in Improving College and University Teaching, pages 27-31. Includes related correspondence., 1955 May (Box 25, Folder 55-4B)
    - 55-4A reprinted in Vital Speeches of the Day, pages 1203-1207., 1955 May 1 (Box 25, Folder 55-4C)
    - Correspondence with Professor Schenck, Hubert, G, of Stanford's Geology Department, about his interest in higher education courses., 1955 Feb-Apr (Box 25, Folder 55-5)
    - Report of WHC remarks at the Western College Association meeting, Panel on Human Resources, Proceedings of the Western College Association, pages 44-47., 1954-1955 (Box 25, Folder 55-6)
    - Correspondence with Lazersfeld, Paul, on the Stern Collection of "Historical Materials on Innovations in Higher Education," and proposed seminar on research training., 1955 Jul-Aug (Box 26, Folder 55-7)
    - Minutes of the Behavioral Sciences Center Seminar on Research Training., 1955 Jul-Aug (Box 26, Folder 55-7A)
    - "The Junior College: Whence and Whither," WHC memo to the Fund for the Advancement of Education. See 75-17., 1955 (Box 26, Folder 55-8)
    - Correspondence and papers about 55-8., 1955 May-1957 Dec (Box 26, Folder 55-8A)
    - "The American System of Academic Government," WHC paper read at the Fall meeting of the WCA, Proceedings of the Western College Association, Fall 1955, pages 25-34. Includes related correspondence., 1955 Apr-1956 Jan (Box 26, Folder 55-9)
    - "The Producers of Research in Higher Education, WHC memo to the Carnegie Corporation, 9 pages. Includes correspondence with Wert, Robert, J., 1955 Dec (Box 26, Folder 55-10)
    - Correspondence with Storr, Richard, J, about the Fund for the Advancement of Education and higher educational history., 1955 Mar-1958 Mar (Box 26, Folder 55-11)
    - Papers related to WHC's five year grant from the Carnegie Corporation to support his research., 1955-1962 (Box 26, Folder 55-12)
    - Correspondence with Quillen, I.J., Wert, Robert J., and Eurich, A.C., reviewing WHC's years at Stanford and his plans for and need for research funds for the future., 1955 Jan-Oct (Box 26, Folder 55-12/1)
    - Correspondence with Anderson, Florence, Secretary of the Carnegie Corporation about how grant money was spent., 1958-1962 (Box 26, Folder 55-12/2)
    - Correspondence with Clapp, Clara F. about obtaining copies of Carnegie Corporation Annual Reports., 1958 Sep-Dec (Box 26, Folder 55-12/3)
    - Correspondence with Gardner, John W., President of the Carnegie Corporation., 1957 May-1962 May (Box 26, Folder 55-12/4)
    - Correspondence with Jackson, Frederick H., Executive Assistant to the Carnegie Corporation., 1957 Oct-1960 Dec (Box 26, Folder 55-12/5)
    - Correspondence with Wert, Robert J., Executive Assistant to the Carnegie Corporation., 1956 May-1958 Dec (Box 26, Folder 55-12/6)
    - Correspondence with Rowan, Helen, Editor of the Carnegie Corp. publication, The Quarterly., 1960 Mar-Apr (Box 26, Folder 55-12/7)
    - Analysis by WHC of the Stanford Conference on the study of Higher Education for the Carnegie Corporation who financed it., 1957-1960 (Box 26, Folder 55-12/8)
    - List of Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching Bulletins, and examples of higher education publications., 1907-1955 (Box 26, Folder 55-12/9)
    - Correspondence with Wert, R.J., Jackson, Fred, and others about the renewal of WHC's grant., 1959 Nov-1960 Oct (Box 26, Folder 55-12/10)
    - Receipts for supplies, equipment, and clerical assistance paid for by Carnegie grant money., 1958-1960 (Box 26, Folder 55-12/11)
    - Correspondence with Chalmers, Gordon., 1955 Jan-Jun (Box 26, Folder 55-13)
    - "The Investigational Function," seven lecture outlines from WHC course, An Introduction to American Higher Education, winter quarter. OVERSIZE, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 55-14)
    - WHC course, An Introduction to American Higher Education. Topics 1-4. 1) "What is Education,'1 2) "How Higher Differs from Elementary and Secondary Education," 3) "How American Differs from European Higher Education," 4) "Why Study Higher Education.”, Fall 1955 (Box 27, Folder 55-15)
    - WHC report to the Ford Fund for the Advancement of Education on the Stephens-Wood Project, 6 pages. Includes correspondence. See also 54-37, 57-30, 62-2, 73-6, 73-7., 1954 Sep-1955 Apr (Box 27, Folder 55-16)
    - Student course ratings and other comments concerning WHC's teaching., 1955 (Box 27, Folder 55-17)
    - Correspondence with Spindler, George, D., 1955 May-Jun (Box 27, Folder 55-18)
    - Correspondence with Gerard, Ralph W.. See also 55-7 and 55-7A., 1955 Dec-1956 Jan (Box 27, Folder 55-19)
    - "The Need for Conceptually Oriented Research in Education," WHC article in the California Journal of Educational Research, pages. 61-66. Includes related correspondence., 1955 Oct-1956 Mar (Box 27, Folder 56-1)
    - "The Haven Function of Colleges and Universities," transcript of WHC talk at Colloquium on the Intellectual and the Challenge of his Culture, Berkeley. 10 pages. Includes correspondence about talk., 1955 Oct-1956 Jan 17 (Box 27, Folder 56-2)
    - WHC remarks at ACE meeting in Washington about improving college and university teaching, published in the American Council on Education Studies Series I: Reports of Committees and Conferences. No. 60, Vol. XX. Includes correspondence with Eurich, A.C., 1955 Dec-1956 Oct (Box 27, Folder 56-3)
    - "What Does a College President Do?" WHC article Improving College and University Teaching. Pages 27-32. See also 60-25., 1956 Apr (Box 27, Folder 56-4)
    - "What Does a College President Do?" WHC address at the inauguration of Lieuallen, Roy E., as President of the Oregon College of Education. 22 pages. Includes related correspondence., 1956 Feb-Nov (Box 27, Folder 56-4A)
    - 56-4 published in College Public Relations Quarterly, pages 6-10., 1956 Apr (Box 27, Folder 56-4B)
    - Papers related to the study of the competence expected of the Stanford School of Education., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 56-5)
    - "Some History and a Look Into the Future," transcript of WHC commencement address at Texas Technological College. 21 pages. Includes related correspondence., 1956 Mar-May (Box 27, Folder 56-6)
    - "Student Personnel Services in Retrospect and Prospect," text of WHC address to the National Association of Student Personnel Administrators, Stanford, School and Society, pages 19-22. Includes related correspondence., 1955 Dec-1957 Jan (Box 27, Folder 56-7)
    - "Education for Breadth versus for Depth," text of WHC address in Hot Springs, West Virginia for the scholarship advisors of Union Carbide and Carbon Co., 23 pages. See also 54-5., 1956 Jun 28 (Box 27, Folder 56-8)
    - WHC book review of Kneller, George F., Higher Learning in Britain for The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, pages 211-212., 1956 Nov (Box 27, Folder 56-9)
    - WHC book review of Kin, David’s, Dictionary of American Maxims, for The Journal of Higher Education, pages 114-115., 1957 Feb (Box 27, Folder 56-10)
    - Correspondence with Mumford, Kenneth, J., 1956 (Box 27, Folder 56-11)
    - "The Concepts of Society and Culture," topic 24 in WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education. Pages 234-248. Includes correspondence and criticisms by students and colleagues., 1954 Jul-1956 (Box 27, Folder 56-12)
    - "Report of the United Armed Forces Institute Study," 19 pages. Includes correspondence., 1956 Sep-Dec (Box 27, Folder 56-13)
    - "Faculty, Rank, Salary, and Tenure Plan," WHC study of Tuskegee University for Patterson, Fred, 17 pages. Includes related correspondence., 1956 Nov-1957 May (Box 27, Folder 56-14)
    - Continued from box 27. (Box 28, Folder 56-14)
    - Student work reports, graduate seminar 308., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-15)
    - Correspondence with Surface, Frank M. of the Standard Oil Company of New Jersey., 1956 Jul-Dec (Box 28, Folder 56-16)
    - Work Records: Mitchell, Marjorie., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-17)
    - Correspondence with Eckert, Ruth., 1956 Jan-1957 Mar (Box 28, Folder 56-18)
    - Correspondence with Cutler, I.W., about WHC's writing guide., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-19)
    - Professional notes accession sheets., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-20)
    - "The Purposive-Act Circuit," WHC lecture outlines. MISSING (not received)., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-21)
    - "What is Education?" topic 1, WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, 20 pages., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-22)
    - "Social Institutions are Organisms," topic 6, WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, 9 pages., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-23)
    - "The Concept of Action," topic 7, WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, 6 pages., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-24)
    - "The Two Power Triads," topic 13, WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, Fall 1956, 11 pages. (Box 28, Folder 56-25)
    - "The Purpose of Social Improvement," WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, 13 pages., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-26)
    - Correspondence with Matthews, Major Allen R., 1956 Mar (Box 28, Folder 56-27)
    - Correspondence with President Wessel, Nils, Y., of Tufts about courses in higher education., 1955 Apr-1956 Apr (Box 28, Folder 56-28)
    - Correspondence with Phillips, J.M., and Seltzer, L.E., of the Stanford University Press about publishing the dissertations of some of WHC's students., 1956 Apr-May (Box 28, Folder 56-29)
    - Correspondence with Paulson, Richard E., of the National Research Council., 1956 Apr-Aug (Box 28, Folder 56-30)
    - Correspondence with O'Brien, Richard F., on a proposal to the Kellogg Foundation., 1956 May-Jun (Box 28, Folder 56-31)
    - Correspondence with Darling, H. Maurice., 1956 Aug (Box 28, Folder 56-32)
    - Correspondence with the University of Chicago about publishing a book., 1956 Jun (Box 28, Folder 56-33)
    - "Who May Educate in the USA?" topic 32, WHC course, An Appraisal of American Higher Education, 6 pages., Fall 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-34)
    - "The Investigational Function, Part Six," lecture outlines from WHC course, An Introduction to American Higher Education., 1956 (Box 28, Folder 56-35)
    - "The Terminology of Commonality Education," topic 39 of 1956 Appraisal Course. (Box 28, Folder 56-36A)
    - "The Concept of Commonality," topic 40 of 1956 Appraisal course. (Box 28, Folder 56-36B)
    - "Conflicting Purposes in Commonality Enculturation," topic 41 of 1956 Appraisal course. (Box 28, Folder 56-36C)
    - "Wanted: A Better Definition of the Concept of Function," WHC class assignment, 4 pages. Includes comments of students., 1957 Jan-Feb (Box 28, Folder 57-1)
    - "Man With an Idea," article about WHC by Rowan, Helen, in Quarterly Report, Carnegie Corporation, pages 3-4., 1957 Jan (Box 28, Folder 57-2)
    - Correspondence with Williamson, E.G., and McGrath, Earl J, See also 57-17. (Box 28, Folder 57-3)
    - WHC memoranda on the terms 'construct' and 'fact', Stanford. 2 pages. Includes related correspondence., 1953-1959 (Box 28, Folder 57-4)
    - Brauner, Charles J’s criticism of the WHC taxonomy. 57, 5 pages. Also related papers., 1929-1957 (Box 28, Folder 57-5)
    - Papers related to Brauner, Charles K's dissertation proposal and the U.S. Office of Education, plus progress reports., 1957 Feb-1959 Nov (Box 28, Folder 57-6)
    - Correspondence relating to the Carnegie Corporation's Princeton Conference on Higher Education., 1931 Mar-1957 Apr 6, 1956 Dec-1957 May (Box 28, Folder 57-7)
    - The Carnegie Conference on Higher Education: Addresses and Discussion., 1931 May-1957 Apr 6 (Box 28, Folder 57-A)
    - Correspondence with other professors of higher education about An Appraisal of American Higher Education., 1957 Apr-Jun (Box 28, Folder 57-8)
    - Correspondence with Jackson, Frederick H. of the Carnegie Corporation., 1957 Apr-May (Box 28, Folder 57-9)
    - Correspondence about WHC visit with Brown, Dyke, of the Ford Foundation., 1957 Apr-May (Box 28, Folder 57-10)
    - Papers relating to an experimental publication, "Epitome" which was to be a book review in higher education. The first and only issue was devoted to Veblen, Thorstein's The Higher learning in America. Includes correspondence., 1957 May-1958 Mar (Box 28, Folder 57-11)
    - Rough drafts of 57-11, including lists of book digests that could be used in future issues. (Box 28, Folder 57-11A)
    - WHC proposal to the Carnegie Corp. about a conference of professors and other students of higher education; includes proposal and related correspondence., 1957 May-Jun (Box 29, Folder 57-12)
    - "The Administration of American Colleges and Universities," WHC paper read to Japanese educators at the Stanford School of Business. Published by the Stanford University Press as a chapter of University Administration in Practice, edited by Oswald Nelson, pages 3-15. Includes related correspondence., 1957 Feb-Jul, 1959 (Box 29, Folder 57-13)
    - Mitchell, Marjorie, job sheets., 1957 (Box 29, Folder 57-14)
    - WHC memo on J.B. And Hefferlin, Earline, work specifications., 1957 Jun 14 (Box 29, Folder 57-15)
    - Text of WHC speech at the Princeton Conference on Higher Education. Includes correspondence with McGrath, Earl J. See Also 57-7., 1957 Apr-Sep (Box 29, Folder 57-16)
    - "A Data Collection and Analysis Systems," Stanford. 6 pages. Describes WHC's professional notes and workbook systems. See also 57-3., 1957 Oct 4 (Box 29, Folder 57-17)
    - Correspondence with Merrick, C. Judson, University of Chicago neurology professor, concerning the concept of structures., 1957 Jan-Oct (Box 29, Folder 57-18)
    - Correspondence with McConnell, T.R., about a proposal to coordinate the University of California and Stanford's programs in higher education. Includes earlier correspondence about Osborn, Alex F., 1950 Dec-1962 Aug (Box 29, Folder 57-19)